sverve.com 2015-03-22

# Sverve Privacy Policy

Welcome to www.Sverve.com (the "Site"), a website operated by Sverve Inc. ("Sverve","HashTip", "we", "us", or "our"). Sverve enables you to save, organize, and search friends' and other people's tips to access them anytime and anywhere, as well as detailed reviews and deals from third party sources (collectively, the "Services"). We developed this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to explain how we collect, use, and disclose information from and/or about you.

By registering with the Site and/or using the Services, you are consenting to our collection, use and disclosure practices described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy describes our practices for both a "Visitor" (which means that you simply browse the Site) and a "Member", which means that you have established an account on the Site (your "Account"). We may refer to a Member or a Visitor as "you".

YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED BY US IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AS WELL AS OTHER COUNTRIES (INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES) WHERE LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY. BY USING THIS SITE AND PROVIDING ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE TRANSFER OF DATA FROM YOUR COUNTRY TO A COUNTRY THAT HAS LESS STRINGENT LAWS, AND THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN CONFORMANCE WITH THIS POLICY.

So we are clear about the terminology we are using, when we use the phrase "Personal Information" in this Privacy Policy, we mean contact information (e.g., name, address, email address, or telephone number) and any other non-public information that is used or intended to be used to personally identify an individual. When we use the phrase "Anonymous Information" in this Privacy Policy, we mean information that is neither used nor intended to be used to personally identify an individual.

### Children.

The Site is not directed to children and children are not eligible to use our Services. Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. We do not collect or maintain Personal Information from people we actually know are under 18 years of age, and no part of our Site or Services is designed to attract people under 18 years of age. If we later learn that a user is under 18 years of age, we will take steps to remove that user's Personal Information from our databases and to prevent the user from utilizing the Site and the Services.

### **Information We Collect From You or At Your Request**

_Personal Information_  
In general, the Personal Information we gather enables us to provide the Services to you and helps us learn more about the use of the Site and/or Services. We collect Personal Information that you submit to us voluntarily at registration and in the course of using the Site and/or Services. To add content to the Site, you must create an "Account" by providing your name, email address and a password. You may alternatively connect to Sverve through Facebook, in which case we may collect your name and photograph from Facebook for the purposes of creating your profile on the Site. When you communicate with us by sending us an email, we will collect and store any information that is contained in your communications with us. 

If you choose to use our "Refer to a Friend" feature, we will ask for your friends email address. We will send your friend a one time email inviting them to visit the site. We do not store this information or use it for any other purpose other than to fulfill send the email at your request.

_Sverve Information_  
Sverve is built on a community concept of sharing tips, advice and comments with our Sverve community. The more tips, the better your experience so we encourage you to provide as many "tips" as possible. We are also an open community, and your name and photograph will be made available to all of our other Members as part of your profile. We collect Sverve Information from you upon your registration and in the course of your use of the Site and/or Services, including through your provision of information to us through an SN Site (defined below). Sverve Information will include your name and profile photograph as well as all comments, tips and other information you provide through the Site and Services. You should know that tips provided by other Members may become part of your Sverve Information when you "like", "favorite" or take other actions about them on the Site. Similarly, your relationships on the Site - your friends and fans - is also considered part of your Sverve Information.

As your Sverve Information is intended by you to be published on the Site, your Sverve Information will not be considered Personal Information under this Privacy Policy, even if it contains Personal Information. We don't think that will bother you, because the very reason you're here is to share your tips with your friends and your community.

_Anonymous Information_  
As you use the Site or Services, certain Anonymous Information may be passively collected and stored, such as your Internet protocol address, domain names, browser type, and access times. We may also use Cookies (as defined below) and navigational data like Uniform Resource Locators (URLs) to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit and the solutions and information for which you searched and viewed. "Cookies" are small pieces of information that a website sends to your browser while you are viewing a website. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your browser until you delete them) to improve your experience on the Site (e.g., by keeping you logged in). Persistent Cookies can be removed by following your Internet browser help file directions. If you choose to disable Cookies, you may not be able to use certain features of the Site or Services.

_Disclosure - Third Party Cookies_  
We may use a third party tracking service such as Google Analytics to track and analyze Anonymous Information from users of our Site. Such third parties may use Cookies to help track user behavior. The use of these Cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these Cookies.

### Our Relationship with Social Networking Sites

The reason you are here is to learn what your friends like and recommend - you want to be part of something bigger. So do we, so we created interfaces that allow you to connect with other social networking websites including Facebook and Twitter ("SN Sites") through Sverve. We work with the SN Site's application protocol interface (better known as their developer API) in a way that allows you to authorize us to access your account on that SN Site on your behalf. In order to provide this authorization, you do not provide us with your user name or password to the SN Site, but you will need to log-in to that SN Site directly through our Site. Once authorized by you, the SN Site provides us a token that allows the SN Site to recognize us when we ask, on your behalf, for access to your account information or to post information. For example, when you click "Connect" to grant Sverve access to your Facebook account, we will import your name and profile photograph from Facebook, as well as your age, ethnicity, gender, marital status, interests, hobbies and the place you live. Similarly, when you click "Like", we will post the applicable information to your Facebook account. You can revoke our access to any SN Site at any time by amending the appropriate settings from within your account settings on the applicable SN Site.

### How We Use Information.

_Personal Information_

  * We will use your Personal Information to:
  * Administer your Account;
  * Target content to you that you are a "fan" of- for example, restaurant tips in a fixed location;
  * Market our products and services (and those of third parties) to you that we believe may be of interest to you;
  * Respond to your requests, resolve disputes and/or troubleshoot problems;
  * Verify your compliance with your obligations in our Terms of Use or other Sverve policies;
  * Improve the quality of the Site and the Services; and Communicate with you about the Site and the Services.

We may also use your Personal Information to create Sverve Information or Anonymous Information records by excluding information that makes the information personally identifiable to you. 

We may send you communications via email about the Site and Services. You can opt out of receiving certain communications from the Site by modifying your Account settings on the Site. Please note that even if you opt-out, we may still send you Site and Services related communications (e.g., emails from other Members).

_Sverve Information_  
We may use Sverve Information in all of the ways we share Personal Information. In addition, we will post your Sverve Information publicly on the Site because, well, that's the point of being on Sverve.

_Anonymous Information_  
We may, through our use of Cookies, keep you logged into our Site, collect your click-stream data, and personalize your experience on the Site. We may use your Anonymous Information to analyze usage patterns so that we may enhance the Site or Services and improve our internal operations and the content of our software and Site. 

We may, through our use of Cookies and web bugs, keep you logged into our Site, track your session history. We may use your Anonymous Information to analyze usage patterns so that we may improve our internal operations and the content of our software and customize the content and/or layout of the Site. 

### How We Disclose Information.

_Personal Information_  
We may disclose certain Personal Information:

  * To third party vendors who help us provide the Services or the Site;
  * To third parties to whom you ask us to send Personal Information (including other Members); 
  * To a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, "Affiliates"), in the event we have such Affiliates in the future, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy;
  * To a company that merges with us, acquires us, or purchases our assets (including in bankruptcy), in which case such company may continue to process your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as they otherwise disclose to you in accordance with applicable law; or
  * If we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to: (a) resolve disputes, investigate problems, or enforce our Terms of Use; (b) comply with relevant laws or to respond to requests from law enforcement or other government officials relating to investigations or alleged illegal activity, in which case we can (and you authorize us to) disclose Personal Information without subpoenas or warrants served on us; or (c) protect and defend our rights or property or the rights and property of you or third parties.

_Sverve Information_  
We share Sverve Information in all of the ways we share Personal Information. But again, since all of your Sverve Information is on the Site already, we're guessing you're okay with our sharing of that information.

_Anonymous Information_  
We may disclose Anonymous Information without restriction.

### Accessing and Controlling Your Information.

You can review, remove and/or change any of your Personal Information or Sverve Information by logging into the Site and accessing your Account. You authorize us to use and disclose any new or modified information that you provide in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and you agree that we are under no obligation to delete or modify information that you have previously chosen to provide us. Please remember, however, if we have already disclosed some of your Personal Information or Sverve Information to third parties, we cannot access that Personal Information or Sverve Information any longer and cannot force the deletion or modification of any such information by the parties to whom we have made those disclosures.

Upon your request, we will close your Account, delete your login information and purge all friend relationships, as soon as practicable, in accordance with applicable law. Any tips you provided prior to closing your account will remain on the Site and in the Services and you will be listed as the provider of tip. We may continue to use Anonymous Information derived from your Sverve Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy even after we have closed your account. In addition, we may retain your Personal Information and Sverve Information to comply with laws, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.

### Information Disclosed to Third Parties

This Privacy Policy addresses only our use and disclosure of information we collect from and/or about you. If you disclose information to others, including to other Members, the use and disclosure restrictions contained in this Privacy Policy will not apply to any third party. We do not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable.

The Site may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by us. We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for the privacy policies of or content displayed on such other websites. When you click on such a link, you will leave our Site and go to another site. During this process, another entity may collect Personal Information or Anonymous Information from you.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is subject to revision from time to time on a going-forward basis. We will post any revised version of the Privacy Policy on this page. If we make any material changes to it, we will also send you notice thereof to the last email address you have provided to us. Continued use of our Services following notice of such changes will indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

### **Contact Us.**

If you have questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us by sending an email to: [info@sverve.com](mailto:info@sverve.com).

This Policy was last revised: Dec 02, 2012
